4-H Clubs of Connecticut Records 1987.0027
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
4-H Clubs of Connecticut Records
undated, [1906]-1977
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1987.0027
84 Linear Feet
The 4-H Clubs of Connecticut originated in 1913 with the establishment of the first club in Mansfield, Connecticut. A part of the United States Department of Agriculture's Cooperative Extension System, 4-H clubs have aimed to educate Connecticut's youth in agriculture, home economics, and new technologies. The 4-H Clubs of Connecticut also strives to imbue its members with important life skills, building character through the teaching of a variety of practical skills. The records consist of the papers of Connecticut 4-H club leader Augustus Jackson Brundage, who helped expand the clubs in the state following World War I, as well as numerous club publications, photographs, scrapbooks, slides, film, and administrative records.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
Unknown.
Arrangement
The collection is comprised of seven series, and spans the period circa. 1906 to 1977.
Series I is comprised of materials relating to Augustus Jackson Brundage, the founder of the 4-H Clubs in Connecticut. The records consists of materials from 1910-1949.
Series II consists of the administrative records of the clubs in Connecticut. The records span the period 1911 to 1977.
Series III is comprised of short courses from 1919 to 1956.
Series IV is comprised of materials relating to the activities and events of 4-H Clubs. The series runs from 1916 to 1966.
Series V consists of subject files from 1914 to 1962.
Series VI is comprised of publications produced by the 4-H Clubs of Connecticut from 1910 to 1969.
Series VII contains photographs, scrapbooks, slides, and films related to the 4-H Clubs of Connecticut from ca. 1906 to 1975.
History
The 4-H clubs of Connecticut are a part of the United States Department of Agriculture's (USDA) Cooperative Extension System. The Cooperative Extension System is a nationwide, non-credit educational network with an office at each state's land-grant university. The program's goals are to provide useful, practical, and research-based information to agricultural producers, small business owners, youth, consumers, and others is rural areas and communities of all sizes throughout the United States.
The U.S. extension program began in the early nineteenth century as informal organizations and associations were formed by American farmers. The early organizations came together to improve upon farming practices, doing so initially through publications such as the American Farmer, which allowed farmers to share new ideas and techniques. In 1862 the federal governement passed the Morrill Act, establishing land-grant universities to educate American citizens in agriculture, home economics, mechanical arts, and other practical professions. The cooperative extension system was formed through the Smith-Lever Act of 1914, linking the United States Department of Agriculture with land-grant agricultural colleges. The act mandated that the federal government allocate population based funds to each state in order to further research and instruction.
The extensions first practical application test came during World War I, as the war necessitated that the USDA use its authority to increase agricultural production and labor. The extension's role during the war helped expand the program and secure its educational reputation. During the Great Depression the extension emphasized farm management and household production, helping many Americans through difficult times and ensuring the survival of individual farms. With American entry into the Second World War the extension once again advocated for increased agricultural production. Through programs such as Victory Gardens the extension was able to increase domestic food production and contribute desperately needed food stuffs to the war effort.
While the number of farms in America has decreased dramatically between 1950 and 1997 the average farm size has actually increased, and due in large part to the work of the extension agricultural production has become more effiecent than ever. Providing education about new technologies, fertilizers, and seeds, the extension has proven to be at the vanguard of this increased productivity in American agriculture.
The 4-H program of the extension has focused on youth education in agriculture, home economics, and new technologies. The 4-H program also aims to cultivate important life skills in youth that builds character and assists in teaching a variety of practical skills. The first 4-H club in Connecticut was founded in 1913 in Mansfield, Connecticut and began as a way to educate youth in the different aspects of agriculture. By 1915 there were more than three thousand youths enrolled in various 4-H clubs throughout the state, and by 1918 there was a club in every county of the state.
Connecticut's 4-H clubs grew rapidly following World War I, especially in relation to the poulty industry. By 1930 the state was holding regional and national competitions, with Connecticut clubs participating in all of them. By 1958 Connecticut had more than six hundred seperate clubs throughout the state, with enrollment surpassing seventy-five hundred youths. By the late 1960s 4-H clubs had been introduced into the urban areas of the state with clubs being formed in Waterbury, Hartford, and New Haven. 4-H club enrollment reached its peak in Connecticut in 1975, when there were 122,158 youths active in the organization.
As of 2000 participation in 4-H clubs is down to approximately 25,000 youths throughout the state, with the majority of participation located in rural areas. The organization continues to promote the education of youths in agricultural practices through hands on activity, as well as the teaching of important life skills.
Scope and Content Note
The 4-H Clubs of Connecticut originated in 1913 with the establishment of the first club in Mansfield, Connecticut. A part of the United States Department of Agriculture's Cooperative Extension System, 4-H clubs have aimed to educate Connecticut's youth in agriculture, home economics, and new technologies. The 4-H Clubs of Connecticut also strives to imbue its members with important life skills, building character through the teaching of a variety of practical skills. The records consist of the papers of Connecticut 4-H club leader Augustus Jackson Brundage, who helped expand the clubs in the state following World War I, as well as numerous club publications, photographs, scrapbooks, slides, film, and administrative records.
Publications (documents); Newsletters; Photographs; Administrative records; Fliers (printed matter); Financial Records; Connecticut (state); Slides (photographs); Notes; Scrapbooks; Correspondence; 4-H Youth Development Program (U.S.); University of Connecticut; Brundage, Augustus Jackson, 1890-
- Series I: Augustus Jackson Brundage Papers, 1910 - 1949
  - Achievement Awards, 1925-1947 (Box 1)
  - Administration, 1929-1948 (Box 1)
  - Art Education, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Birdsongs, undated, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Boys and Girls Week, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Census Data [Agricultural], 1919-1946 (Box 1)
  - Club Agents, undated, 1944-1949 (Box 1)
  - Conferences, 1919-1946 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1918-1947 (Box 1)
  - County Club Committees, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Extension Service, undated, 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - Fairfield County 4H, undated, 1921-1944 (Box 1)
  - Family, [1920-1939] (Box 1)
  - Famine Relief, 1946 (Box 1)
  - The Fire Bringer [story], undated (Box 1)
  - Fish, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Food for Victory, 1942-1945 (Box 1)
  - Forestry, 1920-1933 (Box 1)
  - Game Birds, undated, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Grange, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Hartford County 4H, undated, 1922-1941 (Box 1)
  - History of 4H, undated, 1910-1947 (Box 1)
  - Insects, undated, 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - Junior Achievement, 1917-1925 (Box 1)
  - Leadership Training, undated, 1927-1947 (Box 2)
  - Lecture Aids, undated, 1917-1944 (Box 2)
  - Lectures on Success, undated, 1922-1928 (Box 2)
  - Litchfield County 4H, undated, 1922-1949 (Box 2)
  - Mailing List, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Mansfield Youth Profile, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Manual, undated, 1919-1945 (Box 2)
  - Maps: Connecticut, undated, 1930-1942 (Box 2)
  - Maps: Out of State, undated (Box 2)
  - Membership, undated, 1929-1947 (Box 2)
  - Middlesex County 4H, undated, 1922-1945 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Nature Program, undated (Box 2)
  - New Haven County 4H, undated, 1922-1947 (Box 2)
  - New London County 4H, undated, 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Nutrition and Health Center (Ackerman Photos), 1929-1931 (Box 2)
  - Objectives, undated (Box 2)
  - Older Youth, undated, 1910-1947 (Box 2)
  - Parents, 1946-1947 (Box 2)
  - Plans of Work, 1921-1947 (Box 2)
  - Plant Diseases: Insects and Remedies, undated (Box 2)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 2)
  - Programs, undated, 1940-1946 (Box 2)
  - Publications, undated, 1941-1947 (Box 2)
  - Recognition (Awards), 1926-1932 (Box 3)
  - Reports, undated, 1914-1948 (Box 3)
  - Round-up, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Rotary Clubs, undated (Box 3)
  - Sociology Materials, 1931-1934 (Box 3)
  - Songs, undated (Box 3)
  - Snakes, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Speeches, undated, 1914-1947 (Box 3)
  - Statistics, undated, [1920]-1946 (Box 3)
  - Storrs Grammar School and Community, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Tolland County 4H, undated, 1929-1943 (Box 3)
  - Town Organization, undated (Box 3)
  - Trees, undated, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Wildflowers, undated (Box 3)
  - Wildlife, undated, 1936-1939 (Box 3)
  - Windham County 4H, undated, 1932-1946 (Box 3)
  - Writing Contest, undated, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Writings, undated, 1924-1941 (Box 3)
- Series II: Administrative Records, 1911-1977
  - Annual Reports, 1914-[1938] (Box 4)
  - Awards & Recognitions, 1925-1964 (Box 5, Box 4)
  - Winifred Cheney, undated, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Financial, 1926 (Box 5)
  - Financial: Connecticut Federation of Rural Youth Scholarship, 1948-1957 (Box 5)
  - Financial: Daughters of the American Revolution, 1940-1949 (Box 5)
  - Financial: Development Fund, 1969-1977 (Box 6, Box 5)
  - Financial: Esso Scholarships, 1947-1952 (Box 6)
  - Financial: Expense Accounts, 1928-1965 (Box 6)
  - Financial: Farm Youth Development Fund, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Financial: General Fund, 1961-1970 (Box 6)
  - Financial: Moses Foundation Scholarships, 1949-1953 (Box 6)
  - Financial: Prize Fund, 1961-1964 (Box 6)
  - Financial: Sears-Roebuck, 1948-1960 (Box 6)
  - Financial: Student Aid, 1927 (Box 6)
  - Foreign, undated 1932-1935 (Box 6)
  - 4H Clubs of the Air [Radio Scripts], 1937-1939 (Box 6)
  - 4H Club Statistics, 1920-1961 (Box 7)
  - Grange, undated (Box 7)
  - History, undated, 1911-1953 (Box 7)
  - Institute of Women's Professional Relations, 1935-1936 (Box 7)
  - Mimeographs, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1922-1958 (Box 8)
  - National Club: Commemorative Stamp, 1952 (Box 9)
  - National Club: Committees, 1947-1971 (Box 9)
  - National Club: Conferences, 1927-1972 (Box 9, Box 10)
  - National Club: Congress, 1945-1970 (Box 10)
  - National Club: Economy, 1932-1938 (Box 10)
  - National Club: 4-H Newsletter, 1950 (Box 10)
  - National Club: Programs, 1939-1960 (Box 10)
  - National Club: Reports, 1924-1954 (Box 10, Box 11)
  - Project Agreements, [1914]-1928 (Box 11)
  - Regional Conferences, 1939-1954 (Box 11)
  - Regional Programs, undated, 1950-1957 (Box 11)
  - Speakers, undated, 1936-1937 (Box 11)
  - State and County Conferences, undated, 1915-1970 (Box 11, Box 13, Box 12)
  - State and County Programs, undated, 1914-1958 (Box 14, Box 15, Box 13)
  - State and County Reports, 1914-1970 (Box 16, Box 18, Box 20, Box 19, Box 17, Box 21, Box 15)
  - State and County Statistics, 1916-1955 (Box 21)
  - State Club Senior Conference, 1930-1934 (Box 21)
  - Elsie Trabue, 1920-1940 (Box 21)
  - University Club, undated, 1925-1961 (Box 21)
  - Who's Who, undated, [1914]-1968 (Box 22, Folder Abate-Cox, Box 28, Folder Stratton-Zolla, Box 23, Folder Crandall-Gardner, Box 25, Folder Kahn-McNulty, Box 24, Folder Giddings-Juniver, Box 26, Folder Meader-Pullar, Box 27, Folder Racker-Stotler)
  - YWCA, 1933-1935 (Box 28)
- Series III: Short Course, 1919-1956
  - Junior Short Course, 1919-1955 (Box 31, Box 29, Box 30)
  - Junior Short Course: Newsletter, 1924-1952 (Box 31)
  - Junior Short Course: Statistics, 1919-1940 (Box 31)
  - Tractor Short Course, 1945-1956 (Box 31)
- Series IV: Activities and Events, 1916-1966
  - Eastern States Exposition, undated, 1916-1966 (Box 32, Box 34, Box 33, Box 35)
  - National Club: Camp, 1927-1956 (Box 36, Box 37)
  - Round-up, 1929-1931 (Box 37)
  - State and County Camps, 1929-1949 (Box 37)
  - National Dairy Show, 1935-1941 (Box 38)
  - National Poultry Show, 1919-1940 (Box 38)
  - National Club: World Poultry Congress, 1937-1939 (Box 38)
  - National Club: Social Progress Program, 1936-1937
  - National 4H Club Week, 1945-1957 (Box 38)
  - National Club: World Agricultural Fair, 1959-1960 (Box 38)
  - Regional: 4-H Sunday, 1951-1952 (Box 38)
  - Regional: Meat Animal Show, 1951-1954 (Box 38)
  - State and County Exhibits, 1924-1947 (Box 38)
  - State and County Festival, 1934 (Box 38)
  - State and County Silver Jubilee, 1938 (Box 38)
  - State Fairs and Exhibits, 1923-1960 (Box 39)
- Series V: Subject Files, 1914-1962
  - County Organizations, 1921-1946 (Box 40)
  - Dairy Farm Account Book, 1925-1929 (Box 40)
  - Farm Bureau, 1922-1957 (Box 40)
  - Farmers Clubs, 1923-1934 (Box 40)
  - A.B. Graham, 1926-1944 (Box 40)
  - History, 1914-1948 (Box 40)
  - Junior Achievement, 1929 (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous, [1919]-1948 (Box 40)
  - Publicity, 1917-1919 (Box 40)
  - Recreation, undated, 1916-1962 (Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 40)
  - Vernon Alumni Club and Rural Youth Federation, 1934-1948 (Box 43)
  - Vocational Guidance, 1948-1949 (Box 43)
  - Young Men and Women Committee, 1945-1950 (Box 43)
- Series VI: Publications, 1910-1969
  - Building America, 1936-1937 (Box 44)
  - Connecticut Publications, 1913-[1969] (Box 44)
  - Connecticut Four Leaf Clover, 1928-1945 (Box 44)
  - National 4-H News, 1941-1968 (Box 44, Box 45)
  - Handicrafts, [1930]-[1939] (Box 45)
  - National Publications, 1910-1956 (Box 45)
  - Out of State Publications, 1922-1963 (Box 45)
  - Recreation Publications, [1930]-[1939] (Box 45)
  - Rural Life Sunday, 1943-1962 (Box 45)
- Series VII: Photographs, Scrapbooks, Slides, Films, undated, [1906]-1975
  - S-series Index, undated, 1923-1932 (Box 46)
  - S-series Legend, 1925 (Box 46)
  - S-series photographs, undated, 1923-1940 (Box 46)
  - G.W. Ackerman, undated, 1927-1940 (Box 46)
  - Alumni Recognition, 1964 (Box 46)
  - American Country Life Meeting, 1945 (Box 46)
  - American Institute of Cooking - Cornell, 1954 (Box 46)
  - Analysis of Club Questionnaire, undated (Box 46)
  - Andover Tree Planting Ceremony, 1932 (Box 46)
  - Annual Report, 1925 (Box 46)
  - Automobiles, undated, 1914-1937 (Box 46)
  - Avon Potato Club Boys, 1916 (Box 46)
  - Awards and Recognition, undated, 1948-1975 (Box 46)
  - Birds, 1913-1915 (Box 47)
  - Beef, undated, 1938-1942 (Box 47)
  - Bridgeport, 1917 (Box 47)
  - Buildings, undated, 1922-1939 (Box 47)
  - Calf Club, undated (Box 47)
  - Camp Woodstock, undated, 1929 (Box 47)
  - Camps, 1942 (Box 47)
  - Canning Clubs, undated, 1917-1932 (Box 47)
  - Career Exploration, 1960 (Box 47)
  - Chicken of Tomorrow Contenst, 1959 (Box 47)
  - Clubwork outline, undated, 1917-1934 (Box 47)
  - Conferences, 1930-1933 (Box 47)
  - Congresses, 1926 (Box 47)
  - Cooking Clubs, undated, 1921-1932 (Box 47)
  - Corn Clubs, undated, [1906]-1926 (Box 47)
  - Corn Field, 1913-[1914] (Box 47)
  - Corn Plant, [1913] (Box 47)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1971 (Box 47)
  - [Country Fair], 1936 (Box 47)
  - Coventry, 1932-[1951] (Box 47)
  - Dairy Clubs, undated, 1918-1949 (Box 47)
  - Dairy Food Council, 1926 (Box 47)
  - Danbury Fair, 1920 (Box 47)
  - Demonstrations, undated, 1918-[1953] (Box 47)
  - Development, 1916-1919 (Box 47)
  - Dress Review, undated, 1930-1956 (Box 47)
  - Eastern States Exposition, undated, 1916-1967 (Box 47)
  - Eagleville School Fair, 1915 (Box 47)
  - Education, undated (Box 47)
  - Effect of 4-H Club Members, 1918-1945 (Box 47)
  - Electrical Projects, undated, 1956 (Box 47)
  - Ellington Field Day, 1918 (Box 47)
  - Emblem, undated, 1949 (Box 47)
  - Exhibits, undated, [1914]-1936 (Box 47)
  - Extension Service, 1916-1938 (Box 47)
  - Fairfield County, 1917-1925 (Box 48)
  - Farm and Home Week, [1928]-[1941] (Box 48)
  - Farm Bureau, [1932] (Box 48)
  - Farmers Week, 1920 (Box 48)
  - Fashion, 1931 (Box 48)
  - Field Trips, undated (Box 48)
  - Financial, undated, 1952-1953 (Box 48)
  - Fire Fighters, 1947 (Box 48)
  - Flags, undated (Box 48)
  - Flower Garden, 1913 (Box 48)
  - Foreign Exchange Student, 1949 (Box 48)
  - Forestry, undated, 1931 (Box 48)
  - 4-H Camp, undated (Box 48)
  - 4-H Club Fair, 1960 (Box 48)
  - 4-H Club Weekend, 1942 (Box 48)
  - 4-H Radio, 1934 (Box 48)
  - Four Leaf Clover Newsletter, undated, 1925 (Box 48)
  - 4-H Television, undated (Box 48)
  - Garden Clubs, undated, 1917-1932 (Box 48)
  - Garden Contest, 1949 (Box 48)
  - Garder Diseases Chart, 1963 (Box 48)
  - Gardens, undated (Box 48)
  - Goats, undated (Box 48)
  - Granby Grange Fair, 1932 (Box 48)
  - Handicraft Clubs, undated, 1925-1928 (Box 48)
  - Hartford County, undated, 1914-1939 (Box 48)
  - Health Clubs, undated, 1931-1932 (Box 48)
  - History, 1914-1916 (Box 48)
  - Home Making Clubs, undated, 1921-1962 (Box 48)
  - Home Nursing Clubs, 1928 (Box 48)
  - Hop River Classroom, 1931 (Box 48)
  - Hurricane, 1938 (Box 48)
  - International Farm Youth Exchange, undated, 1948-1950 (Box 48)
  - Junior Club Work Campaign, 1923 (Box 48)
  - Junior Food Army, 1917-1918 (Box 48)
  - Junior Short Course, undated, 1919-1951 (Box 49, Box 48)
  - Lantern Slides, undated (Box 49)
  - Leaders Conference, [1945]-1963 (Box 49)
  - Leadership, 1927-1956 (Box 49)
  - Leadership Training School, undated, 1916-1952 (Box 49)
  - Lebanon Agricultural Club, [1915] (Box 49)
  - Liberty Ships, [1942]-[1945] (Box 49)
  - Lime Rock Agricultural Club, 1915 (Box 49)
  - Litchfield County, 1933-1960 (Box 49)
  - Livestock Clubs, 1923-1932 (Box 49)
  - Mansfield, 1913-1961 (Box 49)
  - Maps, 1922 (Box 49)
  - Meetings, 1924 (Box 49)
  - Meriden Achievement Club, [1916] (Box 49)
  - Middlesex County, undated, 1924-1926 (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1932 (Box 49)
  - Model School, 1913 (Box 49)
  - National Club, undated, 1925-1977 (Box 50, Box 49)
  - Negatives, undated, 1925-1939 (Box 50)
  - New Haven County, undated, 1918-1941 (Box 50)
  - New London County, undated, 1931-1938 (Box 50)
  - Newsclippings, undated, 1916-1944 (Box 50)
  - Newsletters, 1919-1933 (Box 50)
  - North Haven, undated, 1926-1930 (Box 50)
  - Notes, undated, 1947-1964 (Box 50)
  - Norwalk Achievement Club, undated (Box 50)
  - Own Your Own Room Club, undated (Box 50)
  - People, undated, 1914-[1975] (Box 50, Box 51)
  - Personnel, undated, 1917-1957 (Box 51)
  - Picking Contest, [1920] (Box 51)
  - Pig Clubs, [1918] (Box 51)
  - Plainfield Exhibit, 1918 (Box 51)
  - Potato Clubs, undated, 1919-1923 (Box 51)
  - Poultry Clubs, undated, 1916-1963 (Box 51, Box 52)
  - Prize Fund, undated, 1931-1956 (Box 52)
  - Professional Improvement Committee Report, [1941] (Box 52)
  - Profiles of Clubs, undated, 1921-1960 (Box 52)
  - Publications, undated, 1912-1946 (Box 52)
  - Publications Workshop, undated (Box 52)
  - Publicity, 1958-1967 (Box 52)
  - Rabbit Bar-B-Q, 1947 (Box 52)
  - Record Book, undated (Box 52)
  - Ridgefield Boys Potato Club, 1917 (Box 52)
  - Rural Electrification Contest, [1948] (Box 52)
  - Rural Youth, 1934-1947 (Box 52)
  - Sears Roebuck Foundation, 1949-1953 (Box 52)
  - School Gardens, 1913-1919 (Box 52)
  - Scrapbooks, undated, 1916-1973 (Box 52)
  - Scripts to Accopany Pictures, undated, 1934-1941 (Box 52)
  - Senior Conference, undated, 1930-1975 (Box 52)
  - Sewing Clubs, undated, 1914-1932 (Box 52)
  - Sheep, undated, 1917-1959 (Box 52)
  - Short Course, undated, 1950-1969 (Box 52)
  - Silver Jubilee Celebration, 1938 (Box 52)
  - Song and Dance Festival, undated, 1939-1949 (Box 53)
  - Stamford, [1918] (Box 53)
  - State Club Exhibit, 1926-1941 (Box 53)
  - State Fair, undated, 1914-1958 (Box 53)
  - State 4-H Council, 1960 (Box 53)
  - State 4-H Week, undated, 1954 (Box 53)
  - Stunts, undated (Box 53)
  - Summer Camp, undated (Box 53)
  - Telegraphic Report, 1935-1941 (Box 53)
  - [Tent Caterpillars], [1914]-[1915] (Box 53)
  - Tolland County, undated, 1931-1966 (Box 53)
  - Thrall's Turkey Farm, undated (Box 53)
  - Trees, undated (Box 53)
  - Turkey Scholarship Project, undated, 1946 (Box 53)
  - United Nations, [1950] (Box 53)
  - University of Connecticut, undated, [1925] (Box 53)
  - Vegetable Garden, [1913] (Box 53)
  - Waterbury, 1918 (Box 53)
  - Wild Flowers, undated (Box 53)
  - Wildlife, undated (Box 53)
  - Willimantic, 1917 (Box 53)
  - Windham County, undated, [1916] (Box 53)
  - Y.M.C.A., undated (Box 53)
  - Youth Activity Round Table, 1937 (Box 53)
  - National Club Congress [Oversize photographs], undated, 1924-1956 (Box 54)
  - Club Charters [oversized documents], undated (Box 54)
  - National Club Camp [oversized photographs], 1927-1957 (Box 55)
  - Camp Vail [oversized photographs], 1926-1947 (Box 55)
  - University of Connecticut Banner [oversized], undated (Box 56)
  - 4-H Clubs, [oversized photographs], undated, 1940 (Box 56)
  - (Box 57, Folder data_value_missing_be4b01860c42e5326ff89feee5351bff)
  - 4-H Clubs [slides], undated, 1953 (Box 58)
  - 4-H Clubs [slides], undated, 1946-1948 (Box 59)
  - 4-H Clubs, [films], undated, [1930]-1941 (Box 60)
  - 4-H Clubs, [films], 1936-1945 (Box 61)
  - 4-H Clubs [films], 1933-1943 (Box 62)